Elayaraja S Front-end developer

Elayaraja S

Front-end Developer

Phone: +91-9600321809 E-mail: raja5ramani@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/ElayarajaSubramanian

Web and Graphic Designer having 11+ years of experience to secure a challenging position to utilize my skills and abilities in the field that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

Skills

| Web technologies | Tools |
|------------------|------------------------------------|
| HTML5 | Adobe Experience Manager 6.1 & 6.4 |
| CSS3 | Adobe photoshop |
| JavaScript | Adobe illustrator |
| React | Adobe InDesign |
| SASS | Adobe premiere pro |
| Bootstrap | Adobe XD |
| jQuery | |

Experience

Oct 2014 - Present Team lead

Infosys BPM, Chennai

- Increased sales ~ 10% by creating newly designed pages using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
- Implemented new content in AEM 6.1 and AEM 6.4 and played a major role in successfully deploying offer content
- Collaborated with UX team, Content team to sharpen newly designed pages and their content
- Collaborated with dev team to come up with easily manageable Content Fragment Model (CFM)
- Collaborated with dev team to finalize the JSON for new AEM
 6.4 pages
- Conducted daily huddle meetings to discuss challenges and to share some best practices to make the process easy

Elayaraja S Front-end developer

Nov 2013 - Sep 2014 Web designer

Habiliss systems pvt ltd, Chennai

 Created elegant web layouts and icons to helped to get more clients in UK

- Converted PSD to HTML and reduced work load for back end developers team in UK
- Collaborated with back-end dev team to fix UI issues

Mar 2011 - July 2013 Graphic designer

Teledata marine solutions, Chennai

- Created elegant login and landing pages for marine students
- Created detailed PDF study materials using adobe indesign for marine e-learning courses
- Created videos using adobe flash which explains marine concepts in detail for marine e-learning courses

Jan 2010 - Feb 2011 Graphic designer

Abink software solutions, Chennai

- Created attractive web layouts, brochures, logos for multiple level clients like hospitals, educational institutions
- Collaborated with dev team to learn more about programming, database

Education

2005 - 2009 Bachelor of Engineering

JJ College of engineering and technologies, Trichy.

Courses and certifications

- Microsoft HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript Certification
- MS Office and MS Windows Course
- HARDWARE Course
- Type Writing (Higher & Lower) Certification

Key Competencies & Skills

Elayaraja S Front-end developer

- Excellent development, analytical and logical skills
- Capacity to work in meeting deadlines
- Ability to go to the core of the problem and resolve
- Willing to learn and adapt to new challenges
- Have strong interpersonal skills, which provides with the ability to interact with end-users,
 managers and technical personnel
- Self-motivated, quick learner

Rewards & Recognition

- Received spot award for my exemplary performance on handling the project
- Received extra miler award for supporting other teams in crucial projects
- Received site of the week award for the websites which I designed

Personal details

Date of birth 28th May, 1987

Nationality Indian

Father's Name P. Subramanian

Permanent address 63, New street, Thuraiyur taluk, Trichy district, Tamilnadu - 621010

Temporary address No.7, Yamunai street, Ram nagar, Madipakkam Chennai - 600091.

Declaration

I hereby, declare that the information published above is correct according to my knowledge and conscience. I can be held responsible for any discrepancies in the above mentioned facts.

(Elayaraja S)